Hello, my friends.
And welcome to exercise, too, in the complete data structure and algorithms, of course.
So we are going to solve an exercise about the complexity and telling us to find the space complexity
of the function and some so and some a method that returns an integer and it is taking in its parameters
and into array called a I want from you to post the video, get the paper and write down your solution
about finding the space complexity of this function.
Remembered that general rules are finding their space complexity.
So please go back to the previous lesson to find the space complexity and and learn more about it before
solving this exercise.
So we will start making and solving this exercise and finding that space complexity of this function.
If we look at the parameters, we have an end array.
So the integer took around four bytes in the spaced memory.
OK.
So an NRA, an NRA would they would talk about four times and fights for NRA.
For is for integer and and if the number of elements of this array.
We have also two two integers size and some we are declaring it, declaring them so in size four by
four the size and four bytes for that.
So.
Also, we have a variable here, and NTI is declared inside the loop, so till now, we have four by
it for the iterator I.
We have.
Four by four for the some and four by for the size, and the trick in this question is that intégré.
So when you see an array, you have four bytes for the end and and for the length of the array.
So we have four times and bytes for all arrays in theory, has this total memory requirement will be
four mn for the array, plus 12 for the other integers, which is increasing linearly with the increase
in the input value of and hence it is called as linear space complexity.
Imagine that we have an array int array of length five or length 10 or length one million.
This algorithm space complexity will increase according to the add to the space complexity.
According to that, number of elements of this array that it contains so that linear space complexity
is expressed in the arrays and used in one dimensional network.
So that complexity and total for the space complexity is all of NW because we have four and 12 and according
to the big O notation.
And that we have solved many, many exercises and question about them about making the highest degree
in their.
Equation, so 12, it will be eliminated because NW is four and is the highest third, we have four
and a plus 12.
The highest term is for N and that four times and four is constant.
So we remove it.
So it would would have.
As complexity, all of and according to the big notation, this is how we solve the space complexity
and by the way, space complexity that is not being asked frequently in the interviews.
But we should mention it according as an exercise in order to have a complete data structure, an algorithm.
Of course, in next videos, we will start solving about 18 question questions and exercises about the
at the time complex.
So I hope everything is clear.
Please.
Anything you want need to ask.
Comment below to help you in your questions.
The.